Potchefstroom, South Africa

# TianTheunissen



**Contact** +27 83 661 0522

tiantheunissen @gmail.com

### **Affiliations**

MuST, North-West University

CAIR, CSIR

#### **Languages** English [100%] Afrikaans [100%]

#### Profile South African Caucasian Male 27 y.o



#### **Career status**

I am working as an academic researcher in the process (full-time) of obtaining a PhD in computer and electronic engineering with a focus on machine learning. The research aims to provide an improved understanding of the ability of artificial neural networks to generalize. Upon completion of my PhD, I aim to contribute as much as possible to the field of machine learning, either in a purely academic capacity, or in the industry with a strong emphasis on research.

#### **Education**

2018–2020 **D.Eng.** in Computer and Electronic Engineering [WIP] North-West University, South Africa (Thesis: Generalization in deep learning: Bilateral synergies in MLP learning)

2016–2017 **M.Eng.** in Computer and Electronic Engineering [78%] North-West University, South Africa (Thesis: Raw coal ore classification using image segmentation methods)

2011–2015 **B.Eng.** in Computer and Electronic Engineering [72%] North-West University, South Africa (Thesis: Virtual advertisement area identification)

## **Experience**

2019-Now Multilingual Speech Technologies (MuST) Potchefstroom, South Africa

Researcher

Independent and collaborative research efforts. Server administration. Software development. Mentor/advise younger postgraduate students. Publication.

2018 North-West University Potchefstroom, South Africa

Teaching assistant

Give weekly classes (on mathematics) for a bridging course aimed to prepare learners to do a degree in engineering. Test grading.

2016–2017 North-West University

Lecturer's assistant

Give weekly tutorial classes on  $3^{rd}$  and  $4^{th}$  year level signal theory. Test grading. Handling and grading of practical demonstration projects. Test supervision.

2014 Council for Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR) Pretoria, South Africa

Contractor

Required practical work experience. FPGA programming. General debugging.

## **Publications**

Co-Author: Davel MH, Theunissen MW, Pretorius AM, Barnard E. **DNNs as layers of cooperating classifiers**. Proc. Thirty-Fourth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence. 2020. New York

Main-Author: Theunissen MW, Davel MH, Barnard E. **Benign interpolation of noise in deep learning**. Spec Issue. (in development) South African Computer Journal. 2020

Main-Author: Theunissen MW, Davel MH, Barnard E. **Insights regarding overfitting on noise in deep learning**. Proc. South African Forum for Artificial Intelligence Research. 2019. Cape Town

Presentation: **The propagation of class information in neural networks**. South African Forum for Artificial Intelligence Research. 2018. Hermanus

# **Ability and Skill**

**Academic:** Investigative research ability. Technical writing. Communicating abstract concepts. Firm grasp on machine learning theory. Teaching.

**Professional:** Skilled at various programming languages (Python, C#, C++, SQL, etc.). Comfortable in Debian or Windows environments. Can apply learned theory about various software development methods. Applying machine learning concepts in practice.

**Personal:** Excellent English linguistic and grammatical proficiency. Good balance of critical and creative thinking. A self-sustained drive to exceed expectations.

#### References

Current research supervisor: Prof. Etienne Barnard

etienne.barnard@gmail.com

Current research co-supervisor: Prof. Marelie Davel

marelie.davel@gmail.com

**Previous research supervisor:** Prof. Willie Venter

willie.venter@nwu.ac.za